Hello English learners, welcome back to another podcast here with us at EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的播客节目。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we are going to be looking at a very useful lesson because, well, sometimes
今天我们要上一节非常实用的课，因为，嗯，有时候
you need to call a plumber.
你需要叫水管工。
Okay, so first of all, why don't we start with vocabulary preview because I think we
好，那么首先，我们为什么不从词汇预览开始呢？因为我觉得我们
need to know this word, plumber.
需要知道这个词，水管工。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right, so on vocabulary preview today we're going to look at two words and the first
好的，今天的词汇预览我们要看两个词，第一个
one is the one that we mentioned, plumber.
就是我们提到的，水管工。
A plumber.
一个水管工。
So it's a person, a plumber.
所以这是一个职业，水管工。
Yep.
是的。
And a plumber is the person who fixes everything in your house that is related to water, right?
水管工就是修理你家里所有与水有关的东西的人，对吧？
Okay, so he fixes the toilet, the sink, the shower.
好，所以他修马桶、水槽、淋浴。
Yep, that's the plumber.
是的，那就是水管工。
And now the second word is obviously related to plumber and it's water pipes.
现在第二个词显然与水管工有关，就是水管。
Water pipes.
水管。
The pipes.
管道。
So the plumber fixes or looks at the water pipes as well.
所以水管工也会修理或检查水管。
Yep.
是的。
And those are a tube that carries water in and out of your house.
这些是输送水进出你家的管子。
Okay, so water pipes.
好，所以是水管。
You also have different types of pipes like gas pipes.
你还有不同类型的管道，比如煤气管。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好。
Okay, so what are we learning in this lesson?
好，那么这节课我们要学什么？
So in this lesson we're going to be learning how to describe when you have problems with
这节课我们要学习如何描述你遇到水管问题的时候，
plumbing, when you have problems in your sink or in your toilet and how you can describe
比如水槽或马桶出问题，以及如何描述
it.
这些问题。
And so I think we should take a look at our dialogue for the first time and see what types
所以我觉得我们应该先听一遍对话，看看这位女士
of problems this woman is having with her plumbing.
遇到了什么样的水管问题。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
Did you call for a plumber?
是你叫的水管工吗？
Yes, yes I did.
是的，是我叫的。
Please come in.
请进。
I'm so glad you came.
很高兴你来了。
This old house is falling apart.
这栋老房子快散架了。
Come into the bathroom.
进浴室吧。
See here.
看这里。
There's water leaking everywhere.
到处都在漏水。
I see.
我明白了。
Let me have a look.
让我看看。
It seems that your toilet is clogged and that's why it won't flush.
看来你的马桶堵了，所以冲不了水。
Let me just get my plunger.
让我拿一下我的皮搋子。
No, that's not working either.
不行，那个也没用。
I suspect that there's some sort of foreign object in the pipe that's causing a blockage.
我怀疑管道里有某种异物导致了堵塞。
That's what's making your toilet overflow.
这就是你马桶溢水的原因。
Oh, that must be because of my four-year-old daughter.
哦，那一定是我四岁女儿干的。
She is always flushing things down the toilet.
她老是把东西往马桶里冲。
You know how kids are.
你知道孩子都这样。
Yeah, I have a little one myself.
是啊，我自己也有个小孩。
Anyway, these water pipes are really rusty, so they also should be changed.
总之，这些水管真的生锈了，所以也该换了。
That could be causing water to not drain completely.
那可能导致水排不干净。
That might lead to more problems in the future.
以后可能会引发更多问题。
I would suggest fixing this faucet that isn't shutting off properly.
我建议修一下这个关不紧的水龙头。
I could have it all finished by today if it's urgent.
如果急的话，我今天就能全部搞定。
That would be great.
那太好了。
Is it expensive?
贵吗？
Let's see.
让我算算。
I would say about $800.
大概800美元吧。
What?
什么？
That's more than I'm making a...
那比我一个月赚的还多……
All right, well, it sounds like she's having some big problems with her plumbing, but actually,
好了，听起来她的水管问题挺大的，但实际上，
I'm really interested that the plumber makes so much money.
我很好奇水管工赚这么多钱。
That is a very interesting thing, and we're going to talk a little bit about that later
这确实很有意思，我们稍后会聊一聊，
on, but I think we should look at those kind of difficult words that we found in the dialogue
但我觉得现在应该先看看对话中那些比较难的词，
now in Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So we have five words here, all to do with a plumber and water pipes.
这里有五个词，都跟水管工和水管有关。
Now the first word, they talked about that there was water leaking everywhere.
第一个词，他们提到到处都在漏水。
So you have water leaking.
所以是漏水。
Water leaking.
漏水。
So to leak.
漏。
When something leaks, it lets liquid come out when it shouldn't.
当某物漏水时，它会在不该漏的时候让液体流出来。
Okay, when it shouldn't.
好，在不该漏的时候。
So maybe you have a bottle of water and it's closed, but maybe there's a hole in the bottle.
比如你有一瓶水，盖子盖着，但瓶子上可能有个洞。
So it leaks.
所以它会漏。
All right, and so there was water everywhere, it was leaking, and maybe the reason was because
好，所以到处是水，在漏水，可能原因是
the toilet is clogged.
马桶堵了。
Okay, clogged.
好，堵了。
The toilet's clogged.
马桶堵了。
Clogged.
堵了。
Now, what does it mean if the toilet is clogged?
那么，马桶堵了是什么意思？
If the toilet is clogged, there is something that stops the water from going down.
如果马桶堵了，就是有东西阻止水往下流。
Okay, so there's something blocking it.
好，所以有东西堵住了它。
Okay, a clogged toilet.
好，一个堵了的马桶。
Now the plumber said that it might be clogged and he tried to fix it with a plunger.
现在水管工说可能堵了，他试着用皮搋子修。
A plunger.
一个皮搋子。
Okay, so it's kind of hard to describe what a plunger is, so why don't we listen to the
好，描述皮搋子有点难，所以我们不如听听
sound a plunger makes in a toilet.
皮搋子在马桶里发出的声音。
All right, so the plunger is the tool that you use to unclog a toilet.
好，皮搋子是你用来疏通马桶的工具。
Okay, that's what you use, a plunger.
好，那就是你用的东西，皮搋子。
So the plunger didn't work and he wasn't able to fix the toilet and he said that there's
皮搋子没用，他没能修好马桶，他说
something in the pipes causing a blockage.
管道里有东西造成了堵塞。
All right, so our next word, a blockage.
好，下一个词，堵塞。
Blockage.
堵塞。
Well, a blockage is something that stops water from flowing.
嗯，堵塞就是阻止水流的东西。
Okay, so something is blocking it.
好，所以有东西堵住了它。
So you have blockage.
所以是堵塞。
Yep.
是的。
Very good.
很好。
And we have one more word on Language Takeaway and that word is faucet.
语言要点还有一个词，就是水龙头。
A faucet.
一个水龙头。
All right, so the faucet is the part of the sink that lets water come out.
好，水龙头是水槽上让水流出来的部分。
Okay, so you have a faucet in your sink.
好，所以你的水槽上有个水龙头。
Yeah, so you put your hands under the faucet so you can wash them.
是的，你把双手放在水龙头下洗手。
Okay, that's the faucet.
好，那就是水龙头。
Yeah.
是的。
Very good.
很好。
So now that we've learned about these different tools and these different ways of describing
现在我们学了这些不同的工具和描述水管问题的方法，
problems with your plumbing, let's listen to this dialogue another time, a little bit
让我们再听一遍对话，这次慢一点，
slower now, and then we'll come back and take a look at some great phrases.
然后回来看看一些好用的短语。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
Did you call for a plumber?
是你叫的水管工吗？
Yes, yes, I did.
是的，是我叫的。
Please come in.
请进。
I'm so glad you came.
很高兴你来了。
This old house is falling apart.
这栋老房子快散架了。
Come on into the bathroom.
进浴室吧。
See here, there's water leaking everywhere.
看这里，到处都在漏水。
I see.
我明白了。
Let me have a look.
让我看看。
It seems that your toilet is clogged and that's why it won't flush.
看来你的马桶堵了，所以冲不了水。
Let me just get my plunger.
让我拿一下我的皮搋子。
No, that's not working either.
不行，那个也没用。
I suspect that there's some sort of foreign object in the pipes that's causing a blockage.
我怀疑管道里有某种异物导致了堵塞。
That's what's making your toilet overflow.
这就是你马桶溢水的原因。
Oh, that must be because of my four-year-old daughter.
哦，那一定是我四岁女儿干的。
She is always flushing things down the toilet.
她老是把东西往马桶里冲。
You know how kids are.
你知道孩子都这样。
Yeah, I have a little one myself.
是啊，我自己也有个小孩。
Anyway, these water pipes are really rusty, so they should also be changed.
总之，这些水管真的生锈了，所以也该换了。
That could be causing water to not drain completely.
那可能导致水排不干净。
That might lead to more problems in the future.
以后可能会引发更多问题。
I would also suggest fixing this faucet that isn't shutting off properly.
我还建议修一下这个关不紧的水龙头。
I could have it all finished by today if it's urgent.
如果急的话，我今天就能全部搞定。
That would be great.
那太好了。
Is it expensive?
贵吗？
Let's see.
让我算算。
I would say about $800.
大概800美元吧。
What?
什么？
That's more than I make in a day and I'm a heart surgeon.
那比我一天赚的还多，我可是心脏外科医生。
Well, we've got three phrases that you can use when you need to describe something not
好了，我们有三条短语，当你需要描述管道出问题时可以用。
working with the pipes.
所以现在在“流利度构建”环节看看它们。
So let's look at them now in Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Fluency Builder.
So the lady called the plumber and he arrived and well, she described her house as old and
这位女士叫了水管工，他到了，她描述她的房子很旧，
that it's falling apart.
而且快散架了。
It's falling apart.
快散架了。
This old house is falling apart.
这栋老房子快散架了。
So when something is falling apart, it's old and it's breaking slowly.
所以当某物快散架时，它很旧，正在慢慢坏掉。
Exactly.
没错。
So we can say the house is falling apart or maybe this old car is falling apart.
所以我们可以说房子快散架了，或者这辆旧车快散架了。
You can also use it for people.
你也可以用它来形容人。
Oh, I'm getting so old and falling apart.
哦，我越来越老，快散架了。
Very good.
很好。
So you're getting sick.
所以你生病了。
Yeah.
是的。
All right.
好。
Very good.
很好。
Now for our second word.
现在看第二个词。
Well, the woman said that maybe her daughter was flushing things down the toilet.
嗯，这位女士说她女儿可能把东西往马桶里冲。
Okay, so to flush something down the toilet.
好，所以是把东西冲进马桶。
To flush something down the toilet.
把东西冲进马桶。
So before we explain this, let's listen to a toilet being flushed.
在解释之前，让我们听听冲马桶的声音。
Okay, so that's the sound of flushing and when you flush something down the toilet,
好，那就是冲水的声音，当你把东西冲进马桶时，
what happens?
会发生什么？
Basically, you throw something into the toilet and then you flush it.
基本上，你把东西扔进马桶，然后冲水。
So it goes away.
所以它就消失了。
All right.
好。
So flushing something down the toilet.
所以是把东西冲进马桶。
Well, she also talked about the faucet and it wasn't shutting off properly.
嗯，她还提到了水龙头，它关不紧。
Shutting off.
关掉。
To shut off.
Okay.
好。
Shut off.
关掉。
When you shut something off, you turn it off.
当你关掉某物时，你把它关了。
Okay.
好。
So we can say to shut something off or to shut off something.
所以我们可以说关掉某物或关掉某物。
Right.
对。
So, hey, Marco, can you shut off the computer?
所以，嘿，Marco，你能关掉电脑吗？
Okay, or I can say, can you shut the faucet off?
好，或者我可以说，你能关掉水龙头吗？
Exactly.
没错。
Great.
太好了。
So we took a look at these three phrases that will help you describe again, these situations
所以我们看了这三条短语，它们会帮助你再次描述这些
or problems that may happen in your bathroom or with liquids.
可能发生在浴室或与液体有关的情况或问题。
And well, let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll come back and talk
好了，让我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来再聊
a little bit more.
一会儿。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
Did you call for a plumber?
是你叫的水管工吗？
Yes, yes, I did.
是的，是我叫的。
Please come in.
请进。
I'm so glad you came.
很高兴你来了。
This old house is falling apart.
这栋老房子快散架了。
Come into the bathroom.
进浴室来。
See, here.
看，这里。
There's water leaking everywhere.
到处都在漏水。
I see.
我看到了。
Let me have a look.
让我看看。
It seems that your toilet is clogged and that's why it won't flush.
看来你的马桶堵了，所以冲不下去。
Let me just get my plunger.
让我拿一下我的皮搋子。
No that's not working either.
不，那也没用。
I suspect that there's some sort of foreign object in the pipe that's causing a blockage.
我怀疑管道里有什么异物造成了堵塞。
That's what's making your toilet overflow.
这就是导致你马桶溢水的原因。
Oh, that must be because of my four-year-old daughter.
哦，那一定是我四岁女儿干的。
She is always flushing things down the toilet.
她老是把东西往马桶里冲。
You know how kids are.
你知道小孩子都这样。
Yeah, I have a little one myself.
是啊，我自己也有个小孩。
Anyway, these water pipes are really rusty so they also should be changed.
总之，这些水管锈得很厉害，也该换了。
That could be causing water to not drain completely.
那可能导致水排不干净。
That might lead to more problems in the future.
以后可能会引发更多问题。
I would suggest fixing this faucet that isn't shutting off properly.
我建议修一下这个关不紧的水龙头。
I could have it all finished by today if it's urgent.
如果急的话，我今天就能全部搞定。
That would be great.
那太好了。
Is it expensive?
贵吗？
Let's see.
让我算算。
I would say about $800.
大概800美元吧。
What?
什么？
That's more than I make in a day and I'm...
那比我一天赚的还多，而且我……
We heard in this dialogue that this plumber is making about $800.
我们在对话中听到这个水管工大约赚800美元。
That's a lot of money.
那是很多钱。
And actually this in many countries is not far from the truth.
实际上，在很多国家，这跟现实差不多。
That's right.
没错。
For example, in Canada, there is a shortage.
例如，在加拿大，这类人才短缺。
There's not enough of these people like plumbers who can do this type of work so they can charge
像水管工这样能干这种活的人不够多，所以他们能收
a lot of money.
很多钱。
So this type of work is called a...
所以这种工作被称为……
He's not really a professional, right?
他其实不算专业人士，对吧？
Right.
对。
He is a trades person because he works in a trade.
他是手艺人，因为他从事的是手艺活。
Okay.
好的。
So like a plumber, an electrician, a person that paints your house, those are all trades.
比如水管工、电工、油漆工，这些都是手艺活。
And well, it is true because now many people don't want to learn or do these types of trade
嗯，确实如此，因为现在很多人不想学或做这类手艺活，
because well, it's not considered to be such a great job, right?
因为，嗯，这被认为不是那么好的工作，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
But the funny thing is now if you're a plumber and you get your first job as a young person,
但有趣的是，现在如果你是个水管工，年轻时找到第一份工作，
you can make so much more money than a person with a history degree, for example.
你赚的钱可能比一个历史学位的人多得多。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Because there is a shortage of these types of...
因为这类人才短缺……
You can call them professionals.
你可以称他们为专业人士。
Yep.
嗯。
Right.
对。
So well, what about in your countries?
那么，在你们国家呢？
Let us know how these types of trades work.
告诉我们这类手艺活的情况。
Are there many of them?
多吗？
Are there not many of them?
不多吗？
Because well, of course, in different countries, it's a little bit different, right?
因为，当然，在不同国家，情况有点不同，对吧？
In some countries, there are too many tradesmen.
在一些国家，手艺人太多了。
So visit us on our website, EnglishPod.com and tell us all about that.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，告诉我们所有情况。
And remember, if you have any questions about the lesson, you can ask them there as well.
记住，如果你对课程有任何问题，也可以在那里提问。
All right.
好的。
So we'll see you guys there.
那我们到时候见。
And until next time.
下次再见。
Thanks for downloading and goodbye.
感谢下载，再见。
Bye.
拜拜。